Zhaorui Zhang

(+1) 206-387-5798 | uwandrew72@gmail.com | uwandrew72.github.io | linkedin.com/in/zhaoruiz

Summary .

Current UW ECE master's student with 2+ years combined internship and professional experience. Fluent in Python, Java, C/C++, JavaScript and SQL. Previously interned as a software engineer in Meituan and Tesla. Possess practical working knowledge of programming, frameworks, database, and distributed system.

Education

University of Washington

Sept. 2022 - Aug. 2024 (expected)

Master of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Seattle, WA

 Relevant Coursework: Algorithms and Computational Complexity, Data Structures and Algorithms, Computer Communication Networks, Database Systems, Systems Programming, Web Programming, Machine Learning

Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Sept. 2017 - Jun. 2021

Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical Engineering

Shanghai, CN

Work Experience_

Meituan | Software Engineer Intern

Apr. 2024 - Jun. 2024

- Developed a restaurant ranking list using Java and Spring Framework, and generated the corresponding labels as the entrances to the list
- Used Thrift to fetch data from various RPC services, created an API gateway to route requests to different processing strategies, and assembled collected information for frontend calls
- Iterated the Black Pearl Guide's nomination client by adding recommendation reason fields, and utilized MyBatis to store newly added information into MySQL
- Migrated the labels' data source to a label management platform, processed synchronization requests using Kafka and stored updates in KV cache clusters, and added query interfaces for downstream services

Tesla | Software Engineer Intern - Data Platform

Mar. 2024 - Apr. 2024

- Designed and built a data analysis dashboard using Python Flask, which integrates Cell Lab's testing data process and provides data visualization
- Implemented a data pipeline to facilitate batch data processing on raw cell testing data during off-peak business hours, and store the standardized data in the database
- Developed an interactive data visualization page using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and mpld3, and added manual labeling, data filtering and plotting features
- Added user permission control, and utilized Docker to containerize the service for deployment on the server

Hugsi | Software Engineer Intern

Oct. 2023 - Jan. 2024

- Designed and developed the gift language collection quiz module for a cross-platform gift recommendation app using Flutter and Flask, and migrated the quiz from Typeform to native system
- Worked with UX/UI team on user experience optimization by refining page layout and adding data visualization
- Maintained backend API modules to improve login experience, and added password recovery functions
- Adjusted the frontend and backend interaction of the quiz module to improve maintainability and reduce servers' pressure, and optimized backend code structure to improve scalability

Projects

Mini Search Engine: Provides multi-word relevance search and accelerated by inverted index and thread pooling P2P File Sharing System: A tool based on UDP that support content search, file transfer and video streaming E-commerce website: A website that supports product search, bulk purchasing and user personalization

Skills

Programming Java, Python, C++, C, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Development Tools Git, Spring, SpringBoot, MyBatis, Thrift, Kafka, Maven, Flask, Node.js, Linux, Docker, Nginx

Database & Cloud MySQL, Redis, SQLite, Microsoft Azure, AWS